Good evening ladies and gentlemen and welcome to the Intell Extreme Master's Taipei Day 1.
I'm Nathanius, Tony Meat is in control.
How are you doing man?
I am doing well Nathanius.
It is awesome to be back into casting some Starcraft 2.
We got fantastic matches which I'm actually talking about.
The patch kind of changes things and I'm a little bit interested to see.
Let me remind the viewers, Lilbo has been preparing for this match since November of 2015.
This is it?
Right.
He has a tough opponent ahead of him.
Of course we'll be taking you through the round of 8 for the Intell Extreme Master's Taipei.
As you can see, we're going to go right down this bracket.
We got four best of fives for you tonight.
We'll kick it off with Lilbo versus Bjann as you said.
Lilbo preparing a lot for this match.
We'll follow it up with Soul Key Pulse.
We'll have SOS last year's champion against the retired MC.
He'll finish the day with Snoot versus Hero.
Great mix of games.
We got top tier foreigners taking on top tier Koreans.
I got to admit I'm a little bit excited to see MC doing well here as well.
A guy that has not necessarily officially retired but definitely said that he's taking
a step back from competitive gaming and going to be a bit more of a streamer.
Change his Twitter name which in the Starcraft universe we know to be the absolute.
That's it.
Once you take the name of your team out or you add streamer to your name, it's about
as definite as like Facebook relationship.
That's it.
Once you do that, there's really no turning back.
I want to rank it higher than that.
I want to rank it a little bit higher than that.
Even stronger than that.
I do.
I think so.
I know it'll quantify this at all but I just have a gut feeling.
I'll take your word for it.
Like we said, the first match is going to be Lilbo versus Bjorn.
Honestly, with the patch coming in, Protoss players, I don't have a really bad time versus
Zerg but I feel already versus Taren as well.
You have to adjust and whatnot but Bjorn has been the king.
I think a lot of people have been rating him as the best Taren in legacy of the void.
He's the guy that's been playing the longest.
Naturally, he's kind of ahead of everybody.
Most people follow what he does.
I'm sure a lot of Taren's myself included.
He'll be looking to see what he does in these matches just to try to get something to take
away from it.
We're going to start the series on Dust Towers.
We do have all the maps for anyone that is curious.
We'll go from Dust Towers to Lairlack Crest, Orbital Shipyard, Ruins of Seris.
If it goes to map 5, Central Protocol, which I do find interesting.
We had the videos Beyond Vidoed Pryon Territors and Lilboed Vidoed on O'Rina.
They'd rather play Central Protocol for TVP.
You'll Rina gets a little bit weird, especially in the PVT matchup, as we see a lot of
liberator, 1-base, 1.5-base pushes.
Lilboed is the guy that would like to make it weird for his opponent, as opposed to being
on the receptive end of that.
It makes a little bit more sense for me.
Of course, in a best of 5, you're going to get to the directs of the maps a little bit.
You're going to see a couple of weird ones.
I feel like, definitely, Central Protocol does actually fit that bill.
I feel like it does.
I'm interested in this match as well.
Beyond it, as you said, one of the guys that kind of out of the gates, right at the beginning
of Legacy of Vidoed, a lot of people were like, well, beyond.
That's one of the absolute best tearing players you can kind of face.
Of course, Lilbo, we make jokes, but the answer is he is one of the best, if not...
Well, it's actually at this point we just say one of the best non-presents.
And he is what's so cool about him.
He's young and determined.
Because of what he did around BlizzCon, basically announced the StarCraft universe, he's
like, yo, I'm legacy void.
That's my focus.
His results have been good, but not Lilbo good, not WCS champion good.
And he had a major like this beating a big name Korean over in Asia.
Can he kind of make a name for himself?
And in the PBT matchup, like you said, very recently, as in a couple days ago, just became
a matchup that is not what it used to be.
In any time in StarCraft, you have a patch change like that.
Things can get weird.
And I'm expecting this to be a bit of a rougher match for the pro losses.
You know, that patch just kicked in.
And this guy has been so good for a while.
I'll be doing the honors of observing as we see where loaded into game number one for
this best of five here at the Intel Extreme Master's Taipei Day one.
Of course, we're looking at the base of the red tarant player.
He is beyond.
He's been on fire.
If you've watched any online tournaments, be on on fire.
Should just go ahead and say that.
I don't know if everybody can't be on fire.
Well, there's a young opening up probably fast Reaper.
You've seen so often in the top right.
We have the blue pro loss player.
Is any Malayam?
Of course, he is Lil'Bow.
And this is a pretty darn decent map.
If you're a pro loss from my perspective, you've got the very easy natural expansion.
We'll make a comment on this opening from beyond here in a second.
So anytime a pro loss can pretty assuredly guarantee themselves a safe expansion.
They're already liking the map.
The next question on their mind is, well, where's my third at?
And this map does make it a little bit interesting.
There's quite a large ramp leading into it, a little bit exposed.
But because it kind of shares good distance between the three bases, you're not too hyper
worried about drops and getting split up too much.
A fairly good pro loss map, but Nate, you saw this opening from beyond.
Double gas like this.
What do you expect me here?
So there's a lot of Korean tarant players that have been opening up with this build in
a high-grandmaster ladder.
It's pretty much where everyone's looking for builds right now since there's so few Korean
tournaments to watch.
I mean, this is where I look for builds.
This is pretty common.
The marine opening into the fast reactor.
He's going to get a tech lab on this factory when it's done.
He will go for a fast cyclone and he'll build a star port and go right up to liberator.
This is one of the most standard aggressive openings that we see.
He hasn't fully saturated his second gas, but I think it's just to make the timing work
out a little bit better.
Fast cyclone openings for defense with some Marines, and especially with the last patch
made that kind of reduced the, you know, I guess usability of photon overcharge makes
doing pressure to produce a lot more common.
The widow mine opening as well is also pretty common before you go for the cyclone so
that you can afford to start the liberator on time.
I guess it all comes down to how he wants to do it since he is only mining one SCV off
of his second refinery.
But wait, Nate, once he has 16 on those minerals, guess what he's going to do?
So switch over to the rally.
Oh, wow.
This is very...
See, now this is like the respect barometer for me.
If it's a guy who's a little bit sloppy, like say myself, maybe TLO.
He's like, oh, he made a mistake.
How he elated.
What an idiot.
No, but yeah.
And the guy that really kind of made this popular for me was Nanyla.
He was...
His gas is man.
It was like an art on itself, and it was just incredible to watch.
But obviously that's planned.
He wants to have the...
While it is just one base and he's delaying the expansion, you need to make up the difference
with the mineral saturation.
But we do have a target coming out from Lil' Bo.
This is also something very popular in the matchup.
The Oracle, of course, and legacy void has a lot more utility to it than just as a harassing
unit.
What I'm kind of curious to see is we've been seeing some proto-s players in the P2 matchup
band actually in the P2Z as well.
Go beyond just one Oracle.
And it's not like a one-base all-in type of thing, but like a...
I have three or four flying around.
It's kind of an anti-drop.
It's kind of...
I constantly know what your tech is with the scouting ability.
And then of course, you need to make quite a bit of defenses to hold off of.
And we have a proxy gateway going out on the map.
So Lil' Bo's opening up the door to get aggressive, meanwhile, be on.
Heading across the map with this drop.
He's got a widow-mind in it.
He's following this up with a second widow-mind and a liberator.
So not the super fast cyclone rush.
He wants to try to get some damage done.
You know what?
He's in pilot placement, Nate, but if he's not there to charge it, then he does get the...
Here comes the piece.
He's got to pick up the widow-mind.
It does do that.
It's going to give him a chance here to do something.
Where is that modisher, Corey?
He's actually...
He doesn't even have one.
He's going to band in the attack.
Good pull back by Lil' Bo.
It doesn't...
Minimal pro-gloss if any action could be good.
And...
No, I'm just...
Just two.
Okay, oh, he's basically...
He's moving in from the other side, though.
And he's bringing the drop-back at the same time.
The Helians actually ran by during this into the natural expansion.
So up to eight pro-gloss killed.
I guess the Helians managed to come in and make a play.
The Metamat pushed back for now.
People might not liberator is still on the way over.
But are the Phoenix going to move out?
I don't think so.
No, so here's the next question, though.
With those Phoenix out, by the way, this liberator...
It's going to hope to sneak it all in this...
Friendliest stalker in the neighborhood.
Okay, there's...
Could have gotten it.
I know what they were there to do, but they didn't actually liberator...
Is going to be deflected by the Phoenix.
Should the Phoenix be on that half the map?
But here's the next question, Nate.
There's a lot of offensive stuff being warped in just outside the base.
We saw quite a few probes go down, so it's really a question of...
Can Lillbo make up the difference?
Now keep in mind, these Marines are un-upgraded.
They don't have combat shields, no stim, nothing.
So it could get dicey over there.
Yeah, the Phoenix are going to come in to scout this out a little bit.
See what's going on as we have a siege tank finishing up.
There's no mistletoe, but there's no oracles.
With that liberator.
That liberator does show up to kill the probes not reacting at all.
Who's in a lot?
At the same time, he's just trying to make this push up the front.
The tank is not siege.
Stalker's going to try to break this ramp as the Phoenix come into it.
I'm assuming he's just going to try to lift up the siege tank with his Phoenix if he gets
too close.
The tank had to pull back here a little bit of the Marine count getting a little bit lower.
They are going to swoop in here.
One of the...
Keep in mind, one of the Phoenix are fairly low in health.
The Stalkers don't have the highest amount of DPS, so I do feel like with the SCVs and the
tank in the Marines, this is going to be deflected.
Liberators moved into the main base, keep in mind.
And we are seeing some probes.
He's getting more chaos.
Yeah, he's not building anything out of that stargate.
There's nothing at home to defend.
And beyond holds, GG, as he takes game number one in this best of five.
I mean, the Liberator counter attack worked really well with Lilbo wanting to get aggressive,
so it's like, okay, Phoenix are great against Liberators, but not if they're on the other
side of the map.
No, and I feel like this is just Lilbo had a planned kind of...
I don't want to say tunnel vision is almost too negative, but he was definitely like,
I'm going to do a 1.5 base all in.
I'm going to lose...
I lost if you pros in my natural.
Not the biggest of deals.
Of course, I would have liked to have kept them, but I'm warping and going for it.
And I feel like, and this is kind of one of those what if moments, if he picks off that
Medevac with six Marines in the middle of the map, I feel like this could have been actually
a good flip.
His stalkers could have.
The Medevac was very low on health.
It would have been a nice pick off.
And I think when you're holding, especially with SCVs in a position like that, using them
to buffer for you when the Medevac's healing them too is really, really nice, because those
SCVs are obviously like a really important part.
Otherwise, the Marines get overwhelmed very quickly, but a little bit of RNG factor in
this game too.
I mean, we're talking about if you lose them, that Medevac has a big deal.
But also, he was really in his head.
He's like, okay, I lost some probes.
I saw that he did a fairly unupgraded opening, like unupgraded Marines, just a single
widow mine, not facing a lot of tech there.
So in his head, I got to make it way in this and go for this.
But if you would have waited just a few moments, picked off that liberator with his three
Phoenix, which they very easily can do.
And then go into like four or five Phoenix, a slightly more robust economy.
Maybe he cracks that shell, because maybe in that time you're facing two or three takes,
but you can pick them up.
You have more gateway units and you have more fallback options.
So that's the what if of Starcraft and we have a little bit of RNG there.
But I think it's also important to note as well.
In legacy of the void, it's not like you dropped that 100 mineral pile on and you're like,
maybe I attacked, maybe I don't.
But to do that push, you need to build the warp gate there.
Otherwise, your warp ends are very slow.
You can't get your forces there in time.
So once you plop down that gateway, you're saying, yeah, I'm kind of invested into this
attack.
You don't have too many other choices.
And then other things also like the widow mines, you don't have any detection.
You didn't have a robo.
You didn't have an Oracle on the map and good initial defense.
I mean, you kind of talked about that.
He actually had no depression at all.
Impressive that he made that defense to without a without a mother ship core as well.
Because he opened straight four stockers.
Like he didn't build a mother ship court all that game.
Forgotten the elbow does that.
I was I was like, bring over.
You know, where is this?
It was like, where's the photo to overcharge?
That's defensive ability.
Is that mother ship in the photon overcharge?
But he actually trims that from his builds.
And it's interesting because obviously it has an effect.
It's 100 gas that you can tech too much faster.
But I'm kind of of the mind where it's like, yo, low bow is 100,000 times smarter than
me, especially when it comes to start to have to.
But I wonder if that's one of the areas where someone could be like, hello,
bow.
My other ships are pretty great.
And he's like, no, they got nerfed.
They can never be used again.
Literally unplayable.
Well, I think it's still would have helped in that position to some extent.
He builds it later, of course, but he does when he does these all in builds, he actually likes
to kind of cut him out.
Yeah, we are loaded now into game number two of this best of five currently leading one.
Oh, we have the red tarant player in the north east.
We have beyond.
He's been doing super, super well.
Unsurprisingly, as one of the best Terran's patch that helps Terran will definitely keep
them in a good spot.
He's going to be happy about that.
And he is facing off against the Frenchman in the southeast.
We have a little bow.
Rough start to the series.
Yes.
You know, that's, you know, best of five, right?
We've got some time.
There's a lot that can happen.
Yeah, he can feel, I mean, anytime you try a cheese in a kind of doesn't work,
but you don't get necessarily slaughtered last game, you know, had its moments for
a little bit.
Probably could have even to himself.
He's saying, well, I'll put it down this for that differently.
I think it could have been really ahead.
That's kind of okay.
The danger though is best of five is nice.
It's a more expanded series, but you're facing beyond it.
It feels like if you have a favorable map for proto versus Terran, any of a situation
where if you would have made a couple of decisions differently and you would have won,
you got to kind of mentally rein that in because that can be tough.
And little bow is mentally tough.
I think that's that's part of what makes him a champion.
You look at him and some of his fellow countrymen,
petite drogos, DeFano, these are the guys that like when they won,
that was like the first time they showed emotion in the entire run of the tournament.
It's because they're just so in control of themselves are so on top of it.
That's like you mentioned, you know, you get your first draw coming out here to Taipei.
And it's okay.
You're playing against pretty much the juggernaut of like Sea of the Void.
Like, Dion is the 10 that everybody looks at.
You know, we've seen a lot of top Terran players in GSL SSL.
I think what comes to my mind immediately is the guys like innovation that were in big peak form
at the end of part of this warm.
And they just flop super hard.
Like not super creative strategies, not able to make it work.
And guys like beyond there, I think a touted is highly as they are because they've been ahead of the meta.
So to speak just because they play so much and play the lot in the beta.
Place in their style too.
The undis always been fairly a bionic heavy.
And I feel like, especially the TV zero right now as you were in now, we're kind of talking about off camera.
You're talking a lot about this tragedy right there.
A lot of two base biopushes.
But also the TVP matchup, there was some talk about Mac and there's definitely some Swiss army openings
where you see a little bit more diverse units, but it's still very bio heavy.
And it's still very much so comes down to can you drop really well?
Can you parade push even against a pro does that's something we're seeing a lot more of?
There's no colossus storm combinations for the most part.
So you're not facing a death ball.
You cannot possibly rock.
If you got good micro, good macro, you're going to be doing better in legacy.
Yeah, I completely agree in this game.
Pretty slow start is both players going for a little bit more.
You know, going for the economic openings, not that super fast tech rush from beyond,
but he is going for the star port off to bases and still no mothership for a name.
Yeah.
I guess Nerf.
Nerf, I don't care about it.
I don't even use it.
I mean, if we talk about what you need, the mothership core for early on, if you probe scout and he already saw that it wasn't like a super fast,
one base like marine, SCV all in or something like that.
Having the stalkers is I think nice for denying the scout as well because like the SCV kind of dodge around an adept early on,
especially since the adip can't really put on as much pressure versus a low number of Marines as it used to be able to.
No, there's definitely some validity to it.
I think what'll be interesting to see is if he maintains this build order play style because with it becoming a 50 energy photon overcharge,
the amount of time it takes for it to become and there is the mothership core.
But the amount of time it takes for it to be defensively very powerful, like having two or three charges to its name so that it can prolong a defense over a course of time.
It's going to be true to see because as it is right now, he just has stalkers like this.
So as for course, it's going to come out. It's going to have one overcharge, which is all right.
But like, let's say he's facing a three or four barracks stem rush, like he just gets absolutely annihilated and that's it used to be with pro dosage.
It was like, okay, well, if I can eek out this no range colossus, I'm good.
I'm going to hold off all the bio pushes this scan from beyond though.
This is like cat's money right here.
He sees three extra gateways on the way.
Seize the Chrono Twilight Council.
And I think on this patch, especially knowing that you're upon it, opened up with stalkers and is with this mind drop,
he kind of gets a glimpse of his lot of stalkers.
You should be expecting that he's going to be hit with some sort of aggression.
But look at this two name.
I mean, look where that pilot is going to add a gateway right there.
From that position, you can jump up into the main or you can apply pressure on the natural,
which is fairly wide open.
This is this is blink stalker heaven beyond so on top of the game already knows that building a bunker in exactly the right spot.
Of course, to the right of that is also where you can bounce in, but not as critical because that's not in on top of production,
which is the really dangerous spot.
You get on top of that spot and you've got a concave at the top of the ramp and unstimmed Marines are like,
let's go up there boys.
It's not going to be a good push for the turn.
Yeah, we do have a tank out though for beyond and in these low unit count situations,
there are a lot of warpins available for little bow and he's going to start to really start to power him out now as that gateway comes closer to finishing.
Medevac, by the way.
Yeah, the Medevac with the tank being able to pick that up, move it back at home at the proto space.
There's no defenses there.
Oh, yeah, that too.
So what am I?
No detection.
I am.
Yeah, they're just fortunate.
They're trying to blink into the main base.
He does night the siege tank though.
The bunker is going to be able to hold on.
I mean, there's a lot of Marines here too.
I think being able to defensively blink away is also really important.
Oh, he just dies right on the next siege tank, but there's so many Marines here with the SCVs to buffer.
While he's losing probes back home, he's going to be enough nine probes dying.
He's killed four or five SCVs so far.
Keep in mind, of course, beyond still has a lot of forces out on the map as well.
Killing both the tanks is the beginning to something good here.
There is no one reminds the main base I believe.
So his economy is fairly okay.
If you can crack this bunker, this could be the beginning of the end for beyond because he does again,
just have the slow Marines going forward here.
And he's getting the bunker still holding a little bit too long.
And the most important is going to get picked off as well, which is kind of a big deal because that's how he bounces in the main.
So right now, the one says, you can only come to my natural.
Any tanks that I make are going to go over there.
My Marines are going to focus on this location.
And if this defense goes on, by the way, the damage is done to the natural, which I feel like he's killed.
This is a lot of probes.
16 total this game.
There's the fancy micro GG beyond takes game number two.
I mean, I feel like if you're beyond, you make that scan.
You've already opened with a factory and you say, okay, if he's rushing adips, he's going to lose because adips are not as good.
He didn't see a forge or anything.
I mean, not expect, you know, we an attack would come much later to have like plus one adips with a robo with that as well.
So the bunkers were brilliant.
Yeah.
And the tanks were good.
The first blink to kill that first tank was incredible.
Really good decision.
And this is where there's so much protest salty tears in the back of my metaphysical brain.
Like I want to cry about a commenters.
I won't.
But the second blink, which and I know he's thinking is like, okay, if that tank stays, I'm going to pick off a depot.
I'm going to walk around and maybe delay the minerals, but that's not enough damage.
I'm in all in mode right now.
So a blinks for gets the tank, but in doing so, loses the amount of stalkers.
It takes to be a threat to win that game.
And from that point forward, with a natural getting un-unhibited harassed by two widow minds.
As you said, nine plus probes were dying.
I mean, and there was no detection site.
He didn't add a robo and never started.
It was like, this is it.
I got to do it.
Yeah.
No way to actually get rid of those minds, even if he snuck the first tank and then like backed off.
He's like, okay, killed some SUVs, but killing some SUVs isn't going to do it in that position.
No.
The bunker is, I have to say, once again, really, really nice.
And just, you know, making sure to constantly build Marines out of that one reactor barracks.
He had a lot of Marines.
He kept both bunkers filled and had enough moving around that with his SUVs.
He could shut down the attack, which was also really good.
So I feel like you have to be kind of on some level a little bit of a starcraft to Uber nerd
to appreciate that game because I feel like if I would have sat down a friend who's not
super familiar to Starcraft, they'd be like, that was dumb.
I mean, a couple of tanks blew up in the protest left.
I don't understand what's happening here, but the bunker timing, it was preemptive.
He knew where he was coming, picking off the most.
Of course, sealing the deal.
But as you said, continuous production and also kind of a,
a little bit more of a subtle note, but not pulling SUVs too early, by the way,
with that first blink, did not pull the SUVs.
It was on the second blink that he did.
And I think one of the things that Terrence do too often is like, they sit all in,
mode all hands of deck and they throw the SUVs in.
And then they do hold off the attack, but they lose so many SUVs at the protest.
But it's like, wait a second.
I'm not dead yet.
Then they do that data mules, but there's a moment where they think that they'll still have
the little minds and his mineral lines as well.
So would have been.
I mean, it's not unfortunate thing, right?
So you get blink stalkers that fast, but to have high ground vision, then you need your
mothership core, which means nothing at home and everything goes really bad.
It's already to nothing.
I would really feel bad.
And again, this is like Lilbo's guys game plan, let him go for it.
As you say, he's playing the juggernaut.
So again, there's a lot of top notch players to look at this kind of matchup and say,
well, I got to choose to win to have any chance.
Well, if I just do a straight macro game with beyond LLL nerd, I'm going to die.
But I want to see something else from Lilbo because while he has always been
fairly all in oriented, I feel like he's always had the ability to fall back on a pretty strong
mid game. Again, pretty aggressive.
It's always like two or three base aggression, but this like 1.5 base, I don't have like
it. If you counter me at all, I'm just dead because I have everything at the front of
your base. It's not working.
The young is defensively opening up with small drop.
And I think on ladder, a lot of terrain plays are probably seeing that as part of us are
trying different things since the adept, where prison build isn't really, well, it's not
as good as it used to be.
There's a brief update.
It does seem I think Lilbo is just like requested like a break.
He's gone to the bathroom or something.
So referee.
It's been an intense 10 minutes.
Yeah.
It's been a rough 10 minutes.
So it'll be a couple minutes before we get into the next game to see you guys know.
Thank you for tuning in.
Hopefully, hopefully folks having a good evening.
We got a lot more Starcraft to come is we're only potentially one map went away from
the end of this best of five.
It's looking a little bit grim, but again, I
It's a little bit orbital next to yeah as well.
I pretty standard map.
I don't know how many, you know, out of left field builds he has for a TV.
Oh, come on.
For pro.
Us.
We we haven't even begun to cheese you wait.
He's like, we've only been doing adept all in but now that we can't do that, like we open
up the rest of the universe.
There's more.
But yeah, it's actually kind of a nicely timed time out for a little bit.
Not to get to again, like dramatic and in the great narrative.
I want to get super tilted.
No, but yeah, take a minute.
That's actually something that I probably could have done a lot better in my professional
careers.
I played a lot of games or just like, no, get in the next one.
Go, go, go.
And I'm just like the whole time shaking and sweaty and just upset.
But little bit taking a moment here to be like, OK, neither of those things work.
Maybe you smoking a bag get right now.
A pack of bag gets certainly has is how I don't know if bag gets their popular and Taipei.
Well, Frenchman's they don't leave without it.
You can get them.
You can get them anywhere.
Yeah, basically their fingers are baggets and they just kind of chop on
off and then eat it and then rip it off.
Yeah, it's going full sponge out there.
So see you guys know as well for anyone curious about like where we are example.
We're broadcasting this from the ESL studios in Los Angeles, California.
Tomorrow, I believe Apollo, Clarice tomorrow for Americans tomorrow for
Americans.
You're a hardcore European watching this.
First of all, you're awesome.
You're up really late, but it's not tomorrow for you.
Yeah.
So today.
So it'll it's it's in a while.
Technically, when when day two, we know how many hours about it.
I actually have no idea because I had you saw this to you tweet out like,
Hey, Jeff and I are two or casting at six p.m.
Someone tweeted us and said, what is that GMT?
I thought why was going well, it was only on it's only because I was on my phone
that I didn't link him to here.
Let me Google that for you.
Oh, okay.
Okay.
I just gave him straight up.
You gave too many clicks for here.
Let me Google that for you, but it's like.
Yeah.
I think we're eventually going to switch to internet time, which is just you tell
people how many hours until something happens.
Yeah.
That's that's the easiest way I think took me long enough to get.
With European, but I think it's basic.
So basically tomorrow for any any Americans watching in and this I I assume that's
most of you guys.
Thank you guys for coming.
Um, Collaris Apollo, Todd will be out there with Chobra and they'll be doing all
that all that good stuff with the top four.
So I have the semi finals and the grand finals.
It's just like like a tweet.
I don't know.
I don't even know where this comes from, but I appreciate it.
This is a default me on Twitter or in the fact that is a really interesting meme.
I just retweeted something.
That's one of my favorite pictures, by the way.
And you said, Claire's we got to yeah, I got to give credit credits to all those
Nate pictures that I tweet.
Those are all Claire's class actually took those and then and posted them in our.
Oh, group chats, group chats.
We have fun by the scenes.
Like we said, we're just waiting for the players to get back as they were given a
little bit of a break.
It's best five.
So let me ask you this.
And okay, so hopefully you won't answer a little bit versus beyond, but what match
are you most excited for?
What were you looking at and kind of wondering?
I actually think that the most even match is probably Palt Solky just because
Taren versus Zerg is in like it's kind of like interesting state where most
Koreans are doing like these like mass marine tank meta-vac like pushes.
Anyway, kill the Zerg before they get high where you just die because you
don't transition out to anything.
And then you know, obviously then the Ultras come out and Marines aren't very
good anymore.
But a micro still very action oriented.
But Palt is, Palt is the guy that is just been, I mean, everyone knows if you
watch Starcraft, you know, Palt's like the guy that makes big plays.
He's the guy that will be down 50 supply and then somehow get a meta back into each
of the opponents base while simultaneously using like 10 Marines to stop like 10
roaches and you won't know how he's doing it.
But I feel like with the way TVZ is right now, I think Palt's going to give us a
really good matchup.
And I don't honestly know what Solky's going to do.
Most Zerg players as far as I'm aware are still doing mostly that, you know,
either early road Travager aggression into hive or, you know, you kind of just
find a way to get to hive as soon as possible.
Because I mean, the hive tech right now, I think for Zerg, especially against
Aaron, like Ultralisers shut down.
It just shuts down bio really well.
C force to turn to go into other things.
But I honestly, I don't know what Solky's going to bring to the table.
Paul hasn't been streaming as much, probably in preparation for this tournament.
So outside of that, I think SOS and C is very interesting because the way PVP's
been set up, but I don't, I don't know exactly how the last patch effects
it either.
Well, yeah, that'll be interesting.
A lot less photon overcharge.
Adips were a part of PVP, but not as much as it was at the beginning.
It used to be like, they're like phase walking past each other and high
fiveing a whole bunch of where are we going to be?
It was really lame actually, but now it's more of like a scout harassing.
Like you'll open up with two of them.
And if they get in the mirror line, Gigi, unless you have some amazing follow up.
But I'm actually excited for that match up too, because I actually think,
especially later, you see the void.
PVP was in a good spot in the heart of the swarm.
It's in a better spot and legacy the void.
I think it actually, and it's weird because it's been a while since I'm really
excited.
It's not like one base every game either as well.
It's it's actually from a non-prod or macro oriented than ever.
There's people freaking.
Next is first or one gate expanded.
They're coming up better.
Yeah, the from the games that I've seen cast, there've been a lot of long PVP's.
But it seems that players are not back yet.
So we're just going to go to a very short break as soon as the players are back
and ready to go, we'll immediately get into the game.
We won't make you guys wait.
You know, don't have to listen to us.
Dot along all day.
Well, you're going to have a lot more of that coming up.
So we'll spare you for a few minutes.
We'll be right back.
You're watching the Intel Extreme Masters Taipei Day 1.
Welcome back, ladies and gentlemen to the Intel Extreme Masters Taipei Day 1.
We are currently loaded into game number three of this best of five in the top right.
We have the tarant player up to all right now.
He is beyond.
He's kicking ass Jeff.
He's kicking butt man.
He is whipping that poor Frenchman around.
He's been doing very, very well for himself.
And of course that Frenchman in bottom left being Lilbo.
He's got to win three games in a row to keep his dreams alive.
It's looking pretty grim form right now.
I'd say yeah, be a rough trip.
Go south to Taipei.
It's certainly not a short flight from France.
I'd imagine gets beyond.
Kind of gets sat down a little bit, but you know what?
Maybe he turns it around here or the shipyard is one of the better PBT maps.
But he needs to.
He needs to do it in kind of a big way because after this it gets.
He gets a little bit tough.
He's had beyond in a couple of decent positions for himself, but again,
as we kind of talked about, and you pointed out Nate, just not having any defense at home.
Beyond has opened up both times with a very like I'm going to defend your attack.
And I'm going to have very light harassed.
It's going to do game ending damage because you have nothing to stop.
Yeah, I think it's a it's interesting because all not all of those were, you know,
forced mistakes or anything either.
Like, Lobo had an opportunity to pick off that Medevac with a lot of the Marines before he made his all in in the first game.
And then of course game number two, just I really feel like it just came down to be on getting a good scout.
He got a good scan.
He knew everything that was going on is Medevac that had left his base earlier.
Actually saw the pile on that he was going to do the all in from.
So just a smooth, very smooth series from beyond so far.
I don't think he comes into this tournament concerned about playing against Lobo.
I know I think TVP probably, you know, he wouldn't actually have to play against MC or or SOS for quite some time because of the way the brackets set up.
So his next opponent will be a Tarranger Azure because that next matchup down the bracket that we'll be doing as well as Pulse versus
Solky, then there's three out of four pro DOS at the bottom half of the bracket.
So I mean, he's just a lot of these darker players don't necessarily, especially in this form out of a tournament, train like,
I mean, unless they have like four zergs in a row, they're not going to not practice everything else.
He probably played a crap ton of ladder, played with his team.
Probably didn't super look into Lobo, maybe asked a few Koreans like, Hey, face Lobo a bunch.
What does he do? And they probably also the same thing is very cheesy.
So I can all in kind of guys was like, OK, you can kind of see that in his builds.
Like both of his builds have just been very, like you said, that scan found out everything.
But for the most part, too, it's it's not, he's not leveraging very much.
He thinks of himself probably as the better player.
And he's doing very kind of hot issue.
Well, it's not fair to call the whole build Hots is, but the idea of a couple of widow minds and some reins being dropped in your base earlier on.
That's very hot. That's that's that's way back to that.
It's getting buffed by tanks and liberators.
It is interesting to see the omittance of that fast cyclone, which is basically that everybody's go to and legacy of the void.
I kind of expected this to happen to some degree where we would see players maybe skip it occasionally,
but I didn't think we'd still see the really fast starboard openings without cyclones.
So basically saying, OK, I don't need cyclones anymore because the what prison attack isn't as common.
Widow minds still deal stargate units like a fast Oracle very well.
So I'd rather just invest into something that I can also use aggressively, but really faster botics pay here.
Yes.
I'm loving everything I'm seeing so far.
It's going to be a war prison to fall that up.
Well, to fall up the the observers, excuse me, but we're seeing a build from map one here from beyond.
It's going to be kind of a marine widow mine drop with some probably hellians.
I believe that's a reactor being out of there.
Where's that a tech lab?
Tech lab. It is a tech lab.
So maybe a slight variation actually is going to be the two.
I like the Viking though because he's following up with this.
It actually helped him a little bit keep the Phoenix away from his tank and he dropped out of the scan.
And he sees everything.
You see the work.
He doesn't see the workers in finish, but he sees the robo going and he sees the robo bay.
And I think seeing the robo bay early on as a tarant tells you pretty much everything that you expect to know.
I would be really shocked if libo did some sort of crazy colossus all in.
I mean, destructor jock really shocked.
Yeah, that's who's going to do.
But really?
Yeah.
So prepare to be shocked.
You know what, Jeff?
Have you?
Did you like it's never mind?
I'm completely okay.
I was going to say I'm like destructor jobs are what I've seen be really effective.
Collosis are okay.
And then you talking about these hard of the swarm styles.
You're like, you got me doubting myself.
Well, I was watching some Petitro fans in Luba.
They do make losses more Petitro than little bo.
But not here.
Give me to disrupt a drop.
I do like the slightly more defensive opening.
But as I said that though, it's it's.
Oh, he does get the win.
That's good.
And a little bit of damage.
Five ropes though.
Five ropes.
And there's the coach.
Are you going to get it?
No, come on, David Kim.
No, I'm just kidding.
Oh, but yeah, the other pilot one would have absolutely finished it off.
It says a lot of our two reactions.
They just came.
Yeah, Jeff gets away.
You panicking and me with a sigh of relief.
Really?
No, I'm like the perpetual underdog fan here.
I just want.
What was he not looking?
No, probably not.
Beyond is everywhere right now, man.
But with that hit and the widow minds being deflected fairly okay.
Five probes.
But in this day and age, that's more okay than not because it is not being
followed up by a two-base all in.
We saw the third CC from beyond.
So the third next will go down at a decent time here as well.
And now let the great harass begin.
Now double disruptor.
So he's bringing the great balls of fire over to the base.
Really?
He's got the Viking on the right side.
Great balls of fire.
Yeah.
Well, there will be many, many jokes like this made throughout the entirety of legacy.
More so.
Okay, until they change the distrubter into a cube.
I like this one.
I'm in this broadcast.
I was going to say the longer this goes, the more gendels that we'll get reference.
But for right now, the observer winning the MVP award knowing and showing where these
forces are.
And you did say that that Viking is there.
And of course, that would be bad news bears.
It still is bad news bears in terms of how much harass is going to get done.
Oh, okay, we got the Viking doing nothing.
But with that speed upgrade, you can get away from this.
Man, he did manage to get.
I guess he got a couple probes and then backed off.
He doesn't want all the stalkers to be able to blink into range.
I think from this far away, I don't know.
It doesn't hit anything.
Yeah, I don't know.
Yeah, but I don't know if the stalkers could all hit it at once.
So he might lose the stalker is very slowly.
Well, for right now, it doesn't do anything.
So it doesn't have to work.
Oh, he's going to try to pick up a stalker.
Oh, look at Lil' Bo.
He's so on top of it.
Nope.
Very smart.
Okay.
So far, nothing though with the disruptors.
I love this though, because his observer sees it, but he recognizes that the one is a little
bit too tight together for him to get those disruptors in without possibly losing them.
But look at the way his observer is set, right?
He can see as soon as he comes on that ramp.
He wants to be looking for it.
And the scan from him says everything's at home.
Let's never look away from this, by the way, because when he comes down that ramp, I might
do something.
He loaded up a tank.
Here we go.
Here he goes.
The observer's like, yes.
I can't even run away.
Oh, no.
Here we go.
Double disruptors are going to come down.
Oh, my God.
Oh, geez.
So many Marines.
He didn't fire the second shot.
No.
The second one was like, let's go.
He's like running forward with it.
Nothing left to kill.
Okay.
That's okay though.
Good hit.
Oh, that's a very expensive prison.
Oh, it's terrible.
And as he goes for the shot, gets a moronter into the region.
Good hit.
Again, buying some time.
Look how painfully slow the Viking is too.
Yeah.
Vikings are.
Carb Whack here, warp prison.
The thing I love the most about this setup, even as this Viking starts to corner that
warp prison, I think I like most about this setup is the liberator can actually catch a non-upgraded
warp prison.
But since he went fast warp prison speed, nothing beyond makes will ever actually be able
to catch the prison.
We have an engagement here.
Lose it.
There's stalkers move out of the map.
So they're not immediately paying attention, but it's nice to see each tank meta that.
It's going to say both of them, both of them are kind of caught off guard.
It's like, oh, I didn't expect to bump into you.
He runs like, I gotta go home.
There's too much stuff here.
Again, a little bit tentative from.
And look at this.
While running back as these stalkers begin to engage, you got the disruptor in the front.
But he's going to drop all the structures from the back.
The moronters trying to run away.
But focus is down the disruptors and kills them before they're purification.
Purification of this can actually go off.
Those lose the majority of his army though.
And there's just so many darn stalkers here.
While not picking off that warp prison, I believe Lilbo is going to feel fairly confident
taking this fight here.
But he's going to pull back as these are pulled.
Probably the wise choice.
Let the stem wear out as well.
Metavex lagging behind.
Goes here to a favorable spot.
Launches forward.
The purifier.
What is it called?
It's purification.
I know it's a technical.
Yeah.
It's called the Great Balls of Fire that you bust out the actual name of it and you're just
throwing me off.
Yeah.
See, I blame you.
See, at first you lose your trust.
And at the second point you're like, no, they can't possibly need a smart and referring
to generals at the same time.
I feel like Lilbo is like one warp in a way of a add-ups away from just stealing the deal.
Reminds shot though.
It gets the shields off from the rest of the system.
And it goes to stand forward.
Got to be careful.
And get the mine either.
Just constantly pushing out here.
Beyond feels like he's the aggressor pulls out.
Yeah.
I mean, as Taren, I feel just securing yourself on three bases is one of the most important
things you do in TvP.
He doesn't actually need to do much because Lilbo doesn't have a fourth.
Well, Nate, he also doesn't have any forges going.
So I feel like it has to be out.
Yeah, it's not up-raids.
He's got his hand on.
He has to end it now and it's getting hard.
Because as time goes on, we...
He's still eating these mine shots, too.
Oh.
Tactical pause from Bound, and I appreciate that.
And there is the purifying what?
Purification Nova.
Purification Nova going forward.
Here's the fight.
But again, not super favorable, actually, for Lilbo.
I just feel like Lilbo has had such a huge advantage in all these fights, but the advantage
is kind of starting to be mitigated.
Now the liberators in position to do some damage.
We have, I think that's two two upgrades on the bio coming up.
Yep.
I mean, two two is going to be lights out if you're down four upgrades.
He's just going to come down and try to fight now.
Does get three marauders with that disruptor shot, but Warpism is injured, but still standing,
and it's going to be forced back a little bit.
I think these meta-vacs are very low on health.
They don't have any energy.
No.
I don't know if he needed to push down their ramp to fight.
He does still have time on his side with those upgrades, and he has the liberator helping
the whole to high ground.
And that's I think if this does go the way of the pro-doss, going to be the thing that
the young looks back on and regrets the most, I think if this game keeps going, he
might.
Marauders got nervous.
They didn't get nerfed that bad.
The young sweep, I think the most important thing you mentioned there.
No, you said it.
You didn't have, well, I said no.
No, there's no probes in this third.
Oh no, it's because the game ended here.
I was like, I was like, I was like, I was like, I was like, I was like, I was like,
I was like, Jail of probes are gone.
It's like, Jeff, we talked about why he was all in.
We didn't know fourth base.
No forges.
Like, that's a super disappointing thing.
I really do feel like, and I know over my career of casting, we don't need, I don't
need to make excuses.
I have countless times.
But I'm like, this fight is super average.
Patriots for player me and then player eight wins the game immediately.
And I'm just like, what happened?
And probable change to the, but in this case, but in this case, no.
Lilbo was super advantage.
I do feel like going down that ramp was a big no.
No, he had one metabac in Red Hill.
I guess he just felt, he must have just felt so good.
It's one of those instances where the double shot on the Marauder is actually really good.
If you have a great advantage, those Marauders wrecked stockers even harder than they would
have before.
Marauders are shooting stockers.
It's really good.
Like it's never, it's just one shot two shot.
Well, he could be doing it below is like in between his legs.
That's a great shot to behind the back.
That's a good shot as well.
I do, I don't want to say this is not like an Idra Esk leaving of a game where it's like,
well, I mean, you know, one, it's just that he had such an advantage.
You're up against a three base, Terran.
You're only on three bases.
He's got two, two about to finish.
You have nothing.
He picked off all the metabacs.
He still had, I mean, when he stood at that ramp and took the fight against, it was kind
of equal forces.
That was a mistake.
He should have blinked back another warp in.
He used zealots to buff his units and they were kind of walking behind the stockers.
That was a very weird choice.
Adips still tank better.
They still do more damage.
He was facing mostly marauders, but again, Adips are just the better call there.
It's hard to say.
I mean, anyway, it doesn't matter.
Beyond wins.
He's, he's, he gets the three.
Oh, I don't think this is.
It's like from office space like, nah, nah, not going to work here anymore.
You're like, well, he's dead anyways.
Who cares?
Let's start with the next match.
Yeah.
So beyond advances, I know play the winner of the next best of five when we're bringing
you guys.
As you can see, this is the bracket here in the first day of the Intel Extreme Masters
Taipei.
So I'm going to go with the three out.
Oh, wait, it's the winner for next series, which I'm also excited for some tearing versus
erg.
Yeah.
It'll be a good one, of course.
And just to kind of put a cap on that last match, I am happy when it, the third game
was still the best one I feel like of the series.
Definitely the closest.
Little bokeh showing some fantastic disruptor shots, defending the aggression better than
he had in the other two games.
Yeah.
That is, that is another interesting point.
Like his disruptor micro at the beginning was really good.
I think it all turned, I think the biggest thing there was when he, he actually managed
to get a disruptor in the front and two in the back.
And I think, I think a lot of, I think a lot of tarant players would like kind of panic
when they're not surrounded, but, but he, yeah, he, he realized like in his crisis management,
he was like, actually, these two disruptors are not a threat if I kill them while I retreat
because if those two detonate on that army, like the game, I'm certain is over at that
point.
But, and that is, I feel like over time, we're going to see kind of a re-emergence of
a lot of pro-dots because disruptor blink stalker is,
very prevalent in PVP in particular, by the way, but also we see it in PVT and PVZ.
But it's one of those armies that I feel like is it shoots right up to the top as one
of the hardest armies to control.
Stockers are absolute crap unless you control them really, really well.
Once you control, really well, they become amazing.
Disruptors.
I would say are even higher on that kind of radicalness.
Doing them both at the same time is really, really tough.
Oh man.
Combining the two hard things together.
It's insane.
It's, it is, I mean, what army is harder to control?
I feel like, oh, come on.
You can't say that to a Taren.
You know, we all have our go-to answer for the last five years against Prodos.
What's harder?
Well, I agree that blink stalker disruptor is the hardest now.
That was really hard to control.
Is that what you're saying?
With Vikings against Storm and Colossus?
I know.
You had to spread out the Vikings, aim moving forward.
Then you had to use your one hot key of ghosts and get all their spells out of the way.
And then you stem forward all the bile.
And if you're really good, you stepped them back a little bit.
I'm glad I was able to get that out of the way.
I was able to get that out of the way.
Taren, I was like, we're going to go to that ship of the guys like hitting all the wreckies.
That's what it's worth, man.
We're going to go to a short break when we come back.
Your next best of five will be Soul Key versus Paul.
Don't go anywhere.
You're watching the Intel Extreme Masters Taipei Day 1.